What do you wanna tell us?
ما الّذي تريد إخبارنا به أيّها العمّ؟
I'll go ahead and fill you in on everything I know about the sky island.
اسمعوا، سأبدأ بإخباركم كلّ شيء أعرفه عن جزيرة السماء
Nothing's been proven, so you'll have to decide what to believe!
لا شيء من هذا أكيد، لكنّ تصديقكم لكلامي أم لا منوط بكم
Okay, we believe you.
!نعم! نحن نصدّقك
Hold on!
!هذا سريع
There's a strange phenomenon that occurs in these waters...
،ثمّة ظاهرة غريبة تحدث في خليج هذه الجزيرة
Every so often, night will fall in the middle of the day.
يحلّ اللّيل فجأة أحيانًا حتّى إن كانت الشمس تتوسط السماء
Oh yeah, we saw that! Right?
!أجل! رأينا ذلك! صحيح؟
Yeah! It got dark, and then we saw some monsters!
!نعم! حلّ اللّيل فجأة ثمّ ظهرت بعض الوحوش
You mean the giants?
العملاقة؟
There's a theory about where they come from, but one thing at a time.
،ثمّة قصّة تتحدّث عن أصولها لكن انسوا أمرها الآن
This sudden nightfall...
...حلول اللّيل المفاجئ هذا
is caused by the shadows of densely compacted clouds.
تتسبّب به ظلال سحب مضغوطة بشدّة
You mean cumulonimbus clouds?
تقصد المزن الرّكاميّ؟
But it was way too dark for that!
لكنّها كانت أغمق من أن تكون سحبًا
Wow! You're so dumb, chestnut head!
!أنت أحمق أيّها العمّ
When there are clouds, it's not night, it's cloudy!
!يصبح الجوّ غائمًا عند تجمّع غيوم كثيرة وليس مظلمًا
Yeah, cloudy!
!نعم! غائم
Cloudy!
!غائم
Pipe down!
!اخرسوا واستمعوا
There are also clouds known as cumuloimperator clouds.
«ثمّة سحب تُعرف بـ«السُّحب الملكيّة
They tower high in the sky, yet remain static and produce no rain.
إنّها تتجمّع عاليًا في السماء لكنّها لا تنتج تيّارات هواء أو مطر
When they appear overhead, even sunlight is blocked out,
،عندما تظهر عاليًا في السماء، يُحجب حتّى نور الشّمس
causing "night" to fall during the day.
ويتحوّل النّهار على الأرض إلى ليل
According to one theory, cumuloimperators are fossilized clouds
وتقول نظريّة أنّ السحب الملكيّة سحب متحجّرة طفت في السماء لآلاف آلاف السنين دونما أيّ تغيير
That's absurd!
!هذا سخيف! لا يمكن للسّحب أن تتشكّل دون تيّارات هوائيّة
It's up to you to decide if they exist.
لكِ حرّيّة تصديق وجودها من عدمه
I'm not asking you to believe me!
!أنا لا أطلب منك أن تصدّقيني
So, they're mystery clouds?
إنّها سحب غامضة إذًا؟
Pretty much. There's still no real explanation for them.
.نوعًا ما... ما زال الغموض يلفّها
That was amazing, Luffy!
!أنت مذهل يا لوفي
Pay attention. If a sky island really exists...
...اسمعوا، إن كانت هنالك جزيرة سماء فعلًا
then that's where you'll find it!
!سيكون ذلك المكان الوحيد الممكن
Okay, gotcha! Let's sail above those clouds!
!حسنًا، مفهوم! لنذهب فوق تلك السحب
Rise and shine, Zoro!
!انهض يا زورو
Morning already?
أحلّ الصباح؟
Get ready, everyone!
!استعدّوا يا رفاق! أديروا الدّفّة مباشرةً للسحب
Full rudder to–
...أديروا الدّفّة مـ
Now, here's the real issue.
وهنا تبدأ المشكلة الحقيقيّة
Get ready... to put your lives on the line!
!دعوني أبدأ بقول هذا... ضعوا حياتكم على المحكّ
– We're already half dead...
نحن على شفير الموت سلفًا
The Knock-Up Stream is a sea current that shoots into the air...
التيار البحري الصّاعد هو تيّار ينطلق في الهواء
so you can theoretically ride it into the sky. Got it?
بإمكانكم صعوده نحو السماء نظريًّا، مفهوم؟
That's the current that sends ships flying, right?
إنّه تيّار بإمكانه جعل سفينتنا تحلّق نحو السماء، صحيح؟
Nice! So it just needs to shoot us above the clouds!
!فهمت! عليه فقط أن يرسلنا فوق السحب
On a sea current?
على تيّار؟
Won't we just end up smashing back down into the ocean?
لكن ألن ينتهي بنا المطاف محطّمين في المحيط؟
Most of the time, yeah. Timing is key.
ذلك صحيح. في العادة التّوقيت هو الحلّ
In theory, this all sounds simple enough...
،من السهل الحديث عن التّحليق بواسطة التّيّار
but in practice, it's not gonna be smooth sailing.
لكن لن تكون رحلة لطيفة كما تعتقدون يا رفاق
The Knock-Up Stream is a natural disaster.
.التيار البحري الصّاعد كارثة طبيعيّة
Normally, it's supposed to be avoided at all cost.
!إنّه شيء يستدعي تجنّبه في العادة
How exactly does a sea current rise into the sky?
كيف يتصاعد تيّار مائيّ كهذا نحو السماء عادة؟
We've never even heard of anything like that before...
.لم نسمع أيّ شيء كهذا من قبل
– Yeah!
!نعم
Of course, we can only speculate on how that monstrous current works.
في العادة، بإمكاننا فقط أن نخمّن كيف يعمل ذلك التّيّار الوحشيّ
No one's dumb enough to jump in and find out, after all.
لا يوجد من هو غبيّ كفاية ليقفز فيه ويكتشف الأمر
The accepted theory goes like this:
:والنّظريّة المقبولة هي كالتّالي
Deep beneath the seafloor, there are large cavities,
عميقًا تحت قاع البحر ثمّة تجاويف ضخمة
where frigid sea water seeps into them.
وتتسرّب إليها مياه البحر الباردة
Geothermal energy from below transforms all that water into steam,
وتحوّل الحرارة في باطن الأرض تلك المياه لبخار
and the resulting pressure explodes up from the seafloor.
ويتسبّب الضّغط النّاجم بانفجار على قاع البحر
The explosion is big enough to send a large current of water into the sky!
انفجار كبير يكفي لإرسال مياه البحر محلّقة
For about one minute, the sea continuously rises into the sky.
ويتواصل البحر بالصّعود نحو السماء لحوالي دقيقة كاملة
One whole minute?!
!دقيقة واحدة؟! ما حجم الانفجار الّذي نتحدّث عنه هنا؟
The explosions happen five times a month, each at a different location.
،يتغيّر موقع الانفجارات كلّ مرّة ويحدث خمس مرّات في الشّهر
Are you trying to blow us to smithereens...?!
!تريدنا أن ننفجر لأشلاء؟
But, y'know...
...ولكن
trying to describe the grandeur of nature with words and logic is a fool's errand.
وصف ظاهرة طبيعيّة كبيرة بالكلمات والمنطق حماقة
S-So, you're saying
بـ-باختصار، علينا ركوب هذا التّيّار الّذي يظهر خمس مرّات في الشّهر
and just hope the sky island is there?
ونأمل أن يأخذنا لجزيرة السماء؟
Yeah. If you miss you'll fall back down, slam into the ocean...
نعم وإن أخطأتموه، ستسقطون عائدين وتصطدمون بالمحيط
and sink to the bottom of the sea.
وسينتهي بكم الأمر في قاع البحر
R-Roger! Let's forget this sky island business.
!حـ-حسنًا! لننس أمر جزيرة السماء
It's impossible!
!هذا مستحيل
You gotta have the luckiest luck that's ever lucked to make it there!
عليك أن تملك حظًّا أكبر بأضعافٍ من أكبر محظوظ في العالم
We'll be fine! Let's go!
!سنكون بخير! لنذهب
I knew it...
...علمتُ ذلك
"We'll be fine"? How can you say that kinda thing with a straight face?!
سنكون بخير»؟ كيف لك أن تقول أمورًا لا أساس لها بسهولة»
I mean, just look at the Going Merry!
!أعني، انظر لحال غوينغ ميري وستعرف
She's barely holding together!
!إنّها في حالة مزرية
As is, she won't stand a chance against such a terrible disaster!
!لا يمكنها تحمّل كارثة ضخمة كهذه
That's true. Even fresh out of the shipyard, that ship wouldn't stand a chance.
هذا صحيح. ما كانت تلك السفينة أن تصمد وإن كانت في أحسن حال
What'd you say?!
!ماذا؟
Speed, weight, durability...
...السرعة والوزن والقوّة
That boat would be blasted apart in the explosion.
ستُدمّر تلك السفينة بسبب ذلك الانفجار
But... Right...? It has to be... No way... After all...
!لكن... نعم! الأمر... مستحيل... فعلًا
But don't you worry about that.
لكن لا تقلقوا حيال ذلك
I'll have Masira and Shojo help take you there.
سأطلب من ماسيرا وشوجو أن يساعداكم في الذّهاب
After we reinforce your ship, of course.
وذلك بعد تقوية سفينتكم بالطّبع
– Yeah, just leave it to us!
!أجل! دعوا الأمر لنا فحسب
Thanks, guys!
!شكرًا لكما
– They didn't even ask us...
لم يطلبا رأينا حتّى
Don't you get it?
!هل تدرك الأمر تمامًا؟
Get what?
أدرك ماذا؟
Well, for starters...
...بدايةً
That's right! We can only stay on this island for one more day at most!
!أطول مدّة يمكننا البقاء فيها على هذه الجزيرة هي يوم واحد فقط
After that, the log pose will lock onto the next island!
!وبعد ذلك، ستبدأ البوصلة المسجلة بتسجيل مجال الجزيرة التّالية
That's right! That's right! We won't make it in time!
!نعم! نعم! لن ننجح في الوقت المناسب
Seriously, now! You're not a prophet!
!كما أنّك لستَ عرّافًا أيّها العمّ
Do you even know how many days
أشكّ أنّك تعرف، ولكن كم يومًا أمامنا
it'll be till the Knock-Up Stream lines up with the cumuloimperator cloud?
!حتّى يتوافق التيار البحري الصاعد والسحب الملكيّة معًا؟
No, no! How many months?! No, how many years?!
!لا، لا! بل كم شهرًا؟! أو لنقل كم سنة؟
Tomorrow afternoon. If you're going, you'd better get ready!
!غدًا عصرًا... عليكم الاستعداد إن كنتم ذاهبين
There's still some time?!
!لا يمكننا الاستعداد حتى ذلك الوقت
What? If you're so against it, then just quit!
!ماذا؟ انسوا الأمر إن كنتم مرتابين هكذا
You're lying!
!أنت تكذب
This doesn't add up! We just met you today!
!هذا غير صائب! قابلناك توًّا، ألا تتصرّف بلطف أكثر من اللّازم؟
Plus...!
!...وأيضًا
Hold on, Usopp!
!تمهّل يا أوسوب
Pipe down, Luffy!
!اخرس أنت
So you're telling us...
شاءت الصّدف أن يكون الغد أفضل فرصة
You'll even help reinforce our ship and navigate us to the launch point?!
!كما إنك ستساعدنا على تقوية سفينتنا وأخذنا إلى هناك؟
That's way too convenient!
!هذا مناسب أكثر من اللّازم
What exactly are you up to?!
!ما الّذي تخطّط له بالتّحديد؟
Plus, you're Noland the Liar's descendant! We can't trust you!
!كما أنّك سليل نولاند الكذّاب! لا يمكننا أن نثق بك
– Boss! Dinner's ready!
!أيّها العجوز! الطّعام جاهز
Move!
!ابتعدا
Nami my sweet! Dinner is–
...نامي-سان! الغداء
Wh-What? You want a piece of me?!
!ما-ماذا؟! أتريد القتال؟
Whenever daytime night is confirmed in Masira's waters,
،وقتما تأكّدنا من «ليلِ النّهار» في منطقة ماسيرا
cumuloimperator clouds appear in the southern skies the following day.
ستظهر السحب الملكيّة في السماء الجنوبيّة في اليوم التّالي
Judging from its rate of five per month,
،ونظرًا لمعدّل ظهوره خمس مرّات في الشّهر
the Knock-Up Stream will probably be active tomorrow.
فإنّ تيّار المحيط الصّاعد سيكون نشطًا غدًا على الأرجح
It'll happen somewhere south of here.
سيحدث في مكان ما جنوبًا منّا
It's not 100 percent guaranteed, but there's a good chance it'll be tomorrow!
الأمر ليس مؤكّدًا 100%، ولكن احتمالية حدوثه غدًا عالية
I'm glad to have met fools like you.
أنا سعيد بلقائي بحمقى مثلكم
Now, let's go and have some food! Take it easy at my place today...
!لذلك، لنذهب ونأكل طعامًا، لتعدّوا منزلي منزلكم اليوم
comrades!
!يا أصحاب
Food! Hurry, Usopp!
!وقت الأكل! أسرع يا أوسوب
Yeah! C'mon!
!أجل! هيّا
Chopper! Go get Robin!
!تشوبر! اذهب ونادي على روبين-تشان
Sure!
!حالًا
Looks like all we can do is try our best to reach the sky…
...يبدو أنّ كلّ ما بوسعنا فعله هو بذل جهدنا للذّهاب للسّماء
Though in the end, it's up to luck...
...رغم أنّ الأمر منوط بالحظّ في النّهاية
Nami, am I just a miserable coward?
نامي، هل أنا بائس وجبان؟
No, you're also stupid.
أضف عليهما غبي أيضًا
I know how you feel. Now go apologize.
أعرف كيف تشعر، اذهب واعتذر الآن
I'm sorry, mister!
!آسف أيّها العمّ
What the...?! Yuck! Don't wipe your snot on me!
!ما الّذي...؟! هذا مقرف! لا تمسح أنفك بي أيّها الأحمق
Today's booze really hits the spot!
!طعم ساكي اليوم أفضل بكثير
Eat up, eat up! There's plenty more saury where that came from!
!كلوا، كلوا! بدأت وجبة سمك الصّوري الكاملة توًّا
Here!
!تفضّل
Gotcha, salvage bum! That's a tabasco bomber!
!نلت منك يا غبيّ الإنقاذ! إنّها قنبلة صلصة حارّة
You long nose...!
!أيّها الوغد طويل الأنف
Hey baby, get over here!
!يا فتاة! تعالي واجلسي قربي
He's gonna eat me!
!سيأكلني
Stop, stay back! Don't do it!
!ابتعد عني
It's my turn!
!حان دوري
"I saw gold...
...رأيتُ ذهبًا»
in the skull's right eye!"
«!في عين الجمجمة اليمنى
Gold?!
!ذهب؟
That tear-soaked sentence was the last thing Noland wrote.
كانت تلك الجملة المغمورة بالدّموع آخر ما كتبه نولاند
"I saw gold in the skull's right eye!"
«رأيتُ ذهبًا في عين الجمجمة اليمنى»
Noland was executed that same day.
أُعدم نولاند في نفس ذلك اليوم
Even after coming to Jaya, it doesn't make any sense to me.
حتّى بعد المجيء إلى جايا كانت تلك الكلمات مجرّدة من المنطق
"The skull's right eye..."
«عين الجمجمة اليمنى»
Is it referring to an ancient city lost to the sands of time,
هل يقصد اسم مدينة كانت موجودة يومًا؟
or was it an allusion to his own death?
أو ربّما كانت تلميحًا لموته؟
The remaining pages are blank, saying nothing more.
لم يُذكر شيء في الصّفحات الفارغة بعد ذلك
And so, we dive!
!لذلك السبب نغوص
Because our dream lies on the seafloor!
!فحُلمنا قابع في قاع البحر
That's right!
!هذا صحيح
We're gonna fly!
!سنحلّق
Not if you keep eating like that, we won't!
!ليس إن واصلتَ الأكل هكذا
It's gotten pretty dark, but I see it, Bellamy.
تأخّر الوقت كثيرًا، لكنّي أراه يا بيلامي
Prepare to go ashore.
استعدّوا لنرسو
Dim-witted dreamers deserve everything they get!
!يستحقّ الحمقى الّذين يطاردون الأحلام أكثر من مجرّد كدمات
"The day I arrived on Jaya. Entry for May 21, 1122."
«يوم وصولي إلى جايا سجلّ 21 مايو 1122»
– ♪ Noland! Noland! ♪
!نولاند! نولاند
Upon landfall, we heard strange bird calls
عندما رسونا على الجزيرة سمعنا نداءات طائر غريبة»
and the toll of a massive bell coming from the forest.
وصوت جرس كبير صادر من الغابة
The sound from that huge gold bell echoed far and wide,
،إنّ صدى صوت ذلك الجرس الذّهبيّ الضّخم يتردّد بعيدًا وفي كلّ مكان
almost as if showing off the prosperity of a city long past!
!وكأنّه يُعلن عن مدى ازدهار مدينة عريقة التّاريخ
We thought we'd seen it all after living mere decades..."
«ظننّا أنّنا عرفنا كلّ شيء بعد عيشنا لبضعة عقود
– ♪ Noland! Noland! ♪
!نولاند! نولاند
"but confronting this blossoming civilization's transience
لكنّ الوقت العابر الّذي اختبرناه من هذه الحضارة الّتي ازدهرت»
next to the vast, eternal ocean left us speechless!
!لوقت طويل في البحر الواسع تركنا عاجزين عن الكلام
The sound of that bell stopped us in our tracks!"
«!جعلَنا صوت الجرس نجمد في أماكننا
Noland's so cool!
!نولاند رائع جدًّا
Wow! A giant gold bell!
!مذهل! جرس ذهبيّ عملاق
Wait a minute! You like Noland after all!
!مهلًا أيّها العمّ! أنت تحبّ نولاند حقًّا
Look at this!
!انظروا لهذا
Wow! Gold bells!
!إنّها أجراس ذهبيّة
Hey, those don't really look "giant."
لكن، كيف لهذه أن تكون عملاقة؟
These aren't the real deal. They're just bell-shaped ingots.
هذه ليست ذلك الجرس، إنّها سبائك ذهب
We found these three on the seafloor.
وجدنا هذه السبائك الثّلاث في قاع البحر
Ingots?
سبائك؟
Oh! So the City of Gold is real!
!هنالك مدينة ذهب حقًّا إذًا
These don't prove anything.
إنّها لا تثبت ذلك
You could find that much gold in any old ruin.
بالإمكان العثور على ذهب كهذا في أيّ أطلال قديمة
But it does prove that there was a civilization in this area.
لكنّها تثبت فعلًا أنّه كانت هنالك حضارة في هذه المنطقة
Ingots are made to have standardized weights.
صُنعت السبائك بغرض الحصول على أوزان موحّدة
Which means they were used for trade.
ممّا يعني أنّها استُعملت للمقايضة
Yes. And the strange bird calls mentioned before that...
...نعم ونداءات الطّائر الغريب الّتي ذكرتُها
Hey, Masira!
!يا ماسيرا
Whoa! There's more?!
!مذهل! ثمّة المزيد؟
This one's huge!
!هذه القطعة أكبر
That's all of 'em!
!هذا كلّ شيء
Wow! It's so pretty!
!إنّها جميلة
Gold bells and a bird...
...أجراس ذهبيّة وطائر
Do you suppose they were symbols of old Jaya?
هل تعتقد أنّها كانت رموزًا لجايا القديمة؟
Can’t say for sure, but I think they were part of some larger statue.
لا أدري، لكن أعتقد أنّها كانت جزءًا من نموذج ما
This here's called a south bird, and they still exist on this island!
!يُسمّى هذا طائر الجنوب، وهي طيور ما زالت تعيش على هذه الجزيرة
Oh! Do they have weird calls?
هل لديها صوت غريب؟
Yep. Just like the logbook says!
!نعم. كما ذُكر في السجلّ تمامًا
Sailors have long used south birds to–
...استعمل البحّارة طائر الجنوب منذ
Oh, crap!
!مصيبة
What is it?! What's wrong?!
!ما الأمر؟! ما الخطب؟
This is bad! You guys, go into the forest! The southern forest!
!هذا سيّئ! اذهبوا إلى الغابة فورًا يا رفاق! الغابة الجنوبيّة
Huh?! Are you off your rocker?!
!ماذا؟! عمّ تتحدّث أيّها العمّ؟! أأنت مغفل؟
Go catch this bird, right now!
!اذهبوا للإمساك بهذا الطّائر في الحال
Why?! What for?!
!لماذا؟! من أجل ماذا؟
Why do we need a bird?
لماذا نحتاج هذا الطّائر؟
Listen closely! The Knock-Up Stream you're heading for tomorrow
اسمعوا جيّدًا! التيار البحري الصّاعد الّذي ستقصدونه غدًا
is located directly south of this cape.
موجود جنوب هذا الرّأس مباشرة
How are you going to get there?!
كيف ستصلون إلى هناك؟
Just sail straight there, right?
سنبحر مباشرة إلى هناك، صحيح؟
Don't forget! This is the Grand Line!
!نحن في الغراند لاين كما تعلم
Once you're on the open sea, there's no way to get your bearings!
!بمجرّد دخولكم عرض البحر، مستحيلٌ أن تعرفوا الاتّجاهات
That's right!
!هذا صحيح
We're sailing toward ocean, not an island, so we have no compass needle to rely on!
نحن ذاهبون لنقطة ما في المحيط وليس جزيرة، لا مرشد لنعتمد عليه
Then how do we go straight south?
كيف نتّجه إلى الجنوب مباشرة؟
You use the bird's behavior!
!باستعمال تصرّف هذا الطّائر
Some types of animals have accurate, internal magnets
تملك بعض أنواع الحيوانات مغانط داخليّة دقيقة
which allow them to get their bearings.
تسمح لها بالتّعرّف على الاتّجاهات
That means animals have got you beat, Zoro!
!إذًا فأنت أقلّ شأنًا من الحيوانات يا زورو
Like you're one to talk!
!وكأنّه يحقّ لك أنت الكلام
In that regard, no other animal comes close to south birds!
!طيور الجنوب هي الأفضل بين هذه الحيوانات
No matter how vast the land or sea they're thrown into,
،مهما كانت الأرض أو البحر الّذي توجد فيها
their bodies will always indicate the direction accurately.
فإنّ أجسادها ستشير دائمًا للاتّجاه الصّحيح
Anyway, you can't go anywhere without one of these birds!
!على أيّ حال، دون إحدى هذه الطّيور، فلن تستطيعوا الذّهاب
You won't have a chance to reach the sky island!
!لن تحصلوا حتّى على فرصة للذّهاب لجزيرة السماء
– What?!
!ماذا؟
Why didn't you tell us sooner?!
!لماذا تخبرنا بذلك الآن؟
Simmer down!
!كفاكم جدالًا
There's no time! Hurry! Don't mess around!
!لا وقت أمامنا! لا تماطلوا
We gotta go into the forest in the middle of the night?!
!تريدنا أن نذهب للغابة في منتصف اللّيل؟
Don't forget these!
!لا تنسوا هذه
We'll start working on your beat-up ship!
!سنبدأ نحن بترميم سفينتكم المتهالكة
In hindsight, this was no time to be partying anyhow!
!بالتّفكير في الأمر، لم يكن هذا وقتًا للاحتفال
Again, why didn't you tell us sooner?!
ولماذا تخبرنا بهذا الآن؟
Listen! Make sure you catch at least one south bird before dawn!
!اسمعوا! احرصوا على إمساك طائر جنوب واحد على الأقلّ قبل الفجر
It's pitch black!
!الظّلام حالك
Quit pulling me!
!كفّ عن سحبي
It's not my fault! My hands are moving on their own!
!ليست غلطتي! تتحرّك يداي من تلقاء نفسها
My stomach's so full... I don't think I can chase birds...
معدتي ممتلئة. لا أعتقد أنّ بإمكاني مطاردة الطّيور
Where are these weird birds?!
!أين هي هذه الطّيور الغريبة؟
Let's just catch one so we can get back to drinking!
لنمسك بإحداها لنستطيع العودة للشّرب
How did we wind up doing this so suddenly?!
!كيف انتهى بنا الأمر نقوم بهذا فجأة؟
You're in the way!
!ابتعد عنّي
Oh man, why couldn't he have told us during the day?
!ألم يكن بمقدوره إخبارنا خلال النّهار؟
Hey, where are the birds?
أخبرني، أين الطّيور؟
If we knew that, we wouldn't be looking for them!
إن كنّا نعرف أين هي ما كنّا لنبحث عنها
Our only clue is that they have a weird call...
دليلنا الوحيد هو صرخاتها الغريبة
...and they look just like that gold statue.
وتبدو مثل ذلك التّمثال الذّهبيّ
Does such a strange-looking bird really exist?
هل هنالك طائر غبيّ المظهر كذاك حقًّا؟
"Weird call" is way too vague! What do we even do with that?!
!كما أنّ «صرخة غريبة» هو وصف غامض للغاية، كيف سنعرفه؟
He said we'd know once we're in the forest...
...قال ذلك العم أنّنا سنعرف بمجرّد دخولنا الغابة
– A weird call!
!صرخة غريبة
That's it!
!هذه هي
Alright!
!حسنٌ
Well, there's no turning back now.
!لا خيار آخر أمامنا الآن
We've got three nets. Let's split up and search!
لدينا ثلاث شبكات لذا سننفصل إلى ثلاث مجموعات ونبحث
– Right!
!أجل
Okay! Let's go beat up those weird birds!
!هيّا بنا! لنوسع تلك الطّيور ضربًا
You mean catch!
!تقصد لنمسك بها
Don't worry!
!لا تقلقي! مهما كان ما سنلقاه، فسأحميك يا نامي-سان
And me, Sanji?
!ماذا عنّي يا سانجي-كن؟
Hell if I care! Grow a pair!
!لا أهتمّ لأمرك! كفّ عن التّصرّف بقلّة ثقة
Whatever. Let's just catch a bird so we can get out of here!
في كلّ الأحوال، لنمسك بالطّائر لنتمكّن من مغادرة هذه الغابة
Let's start by listening closely for that bird we heard earlier.
لنبدأ بالإصغاء جيّدًا لصرخة الطّائر الّتي سمعناها قبل قليل
Hey, that's it!
!تلك هي
You...!
!وغد
What are you catching me for?!
!لماذا تمسك بي أنا؟
Oh, Nami! That's a cool thing you got on! Where'd you get it?
!نامي! ذلك الشّيء الّذي عليك رائع، من أين حصلتِ عليه؟
What?
ماذا؟
Spider!
!عنكبوت
Why, it's just a spider. Come here, you poor thing.
!إنّه مجرّد عنكبوت! أيّها المسكين تعال
Spiders are nasty, moron! Get rid of it!
!العناكب مقرفة أيّها الأحمق! ارمه بعيدًا من هنا
Get away from it, Usopp! It's probably venomous!
!ابتعد عنه يا أوسوب! لا بدّ أنّه سامّ
They're falling from the trees!
!إنّها تسقط من الأشجار
This is too gross!
!هذا مقرف جدًّا
It's probably a species of tarantula!
!لا بدّ أنّها من فصيلة الرّتيلاء
It's fine! They won't bite if you don't startle them!
!لا بأس! لن تقذفنا بأيّ سمّ ما دمنا لن نفعل لها أيّ شيء
I used to have spider fights as a kid!
!اعتدت أن أقاتل العناكب في الماضي
Well, you can count me out when it comes to creepy-crawlies!
!لا تعتمد عليّ أبدًا عندما يتعلّق الأمر بالحشرات المقزّزة مثلها
Same here, I hate them! Hate them! Hurry up and get rid of it!
!وأنا أيضًا! أكرهها حقًّا! أمقتها! أسرع وارمه بعيدًا
Oh? But those moths and centipedes don't bother you?
ولكن ألا تنزعجون من ذلك العثّ والحريش؟
I hate moths and centipedes too!
!أكره العثّ والحريش
Ahh! Don't leave me behind!
!كلّا! لا تتركوني وحدي
I hear screams...
...أسمع صرخات
Forget about 'em.
انسي أمرهم
A centipede, huh? It's pretty damn big...
حريش؟ إنّه ضخم
You didn't have to kill it. Poor thing...
ليس من اللّطيف قتل كلّ شيء، يا لذلك المسكين
That's what it gets for trying to attack me.
هذا ما يستحقّه لمحاولته الهجوم عليّ
But...
...لكن
What?!
!ماذا؟
We just came from that way.
أتينا من هناك توًّا
That bird call... This way.
إنّها صرخة الطّائر مِن هنا
Watch out for that quagmire.
انتبه للمستنقع
Hey! Wait for–
!مهلًا! انتظري
Gotcha!
!أمسكتك
Check it out, Chopper! An Atlas beetle!
!انظر يا تشوبر! إنّها أطلس
An Atlas...?
أطلس؟
Yup! Atlases and Hercules are
نعم
Really? Beetles?
فعلًا؟ الخنافس؟
You never heard of 'em?! They're super hard to catch!
!ألم تسمع بها من قبل؟ الإمساك بها صعب جدًّا
Which is better, them or the One Piece?!
!أيّهما أكثر إذهالًا، هي أم «الون بيس»؟
That's hard!
!خيار صعب
Luffy! There's something here, too!
!لوفي! ثمّة واحدة هنا أيضًا
Whoa, it's a Miyama beetle!
!إنّها خنفساء الأيل
Catch it!
!أمسكها
It flew away!
!لقد طارت
Why, you...!
!تعالي
After it! Don't let it get away!
!خلفها! لا تدعها تهرب
A beehive! Run!
!خليّة نحل! اهرب
What's up with this forest?!
!ما قصّة هذه الغابة؟
Luffy, up there!
!لوفي! انظر هناك
It's that bird!
!إنّه ذلك الطّائر
He's the one dropping the beehives!
!لقد أوقع خليّة النّحل
Huh?!
!ماذا؟ هل قال شيئًا ما؟
He said, "I shall execute any who invade this forest!"
«!قال: «سأقتلكم لاقتحامكم هذه الغابة
Now, now, boy! Don't go making us mad!
!مهلًا، مهلًا يا فتى! لا تثر غضبنا
It's rude to show up in the middle of the night and demand gold, kiddos.
ليس من اللّطيف الظّهور ليلًا هكذا والمطالبة بالذّهب يا أطفال
Beat it! We're busy right now!
!غادروا! لدينا عمل لننهيه
Bodyguards, huh?
هل أنتما حارساه؟
Back at the pub, I heard a real tearjerker...
بالتّفكير في الأمر، كان هنالك قرصان اسمه كريكت فعلًا
about a pirate named Mont Blanc Cricket and his family.
سمعتُ قصّة عائلة مونبلان الحزينة في الحانة
It brought me to tears.
!لقد أثّرت بي
Nothing's better than treasure someone else struggled and suffered for!
الكنوز الّتي كافح أحد آخر للحصول عليها لديها طعم خاصّ بها
Wanna know what people call me?
أتريدون معرفة بماذا يصفني الناس؟
The Hyena!
!الضّبع